As you can see, the metadata in the input form is grouped into six different categories.
The metadata in the first category "Required" is mandatory,
if this information is not provided, it will not be possible to archive your data.
In order to enter your metadata, click on the first category
and you can see how the form expands.
These six metadata fields in the "Required" category are mandatory and must be filled in.
To get started, go to the first section for identifiers.
Use the drop-down menu to select the identifier you want to assign to your data.
For example, if your data is already published, this could be a DOI,
a Digital Object Identifier.
When the type of identifier is selected, you will see that another field appears.
Here you can now enter the DOI itself.
Please note that some of the identifiers, such as a DOI, may have a specific structure.
If your entry does not have the correct form,
the red colouring will indicate that there is an error, so that you can check your entry.
In general, if you are not sure what each of the fields mean,
you can find further information for every field by using the information symbol.
To hide the additional information, just click on the symbol again.
If you would like to enter an additional identifier for your data -
for example a project-specific identifier, just use the "Add Identifier" button.
As you can see, a new input field has been added.
If you change your mind and decide you don´t need this additional identifier
you can simply delete it from the form.
Just use the recycle bin symbol to the left of the input field.
Please note that at least one identifier must be present, as this is a mandatory field.
All other metadata in this form, both required and optional,
can be entered in the same way as just shown.
Once you've finished entering your metadata, don't forget to save your input
using the “Save” button in the bottom right-hand corner.
If you close the form without saving, all your entries will be lost.